<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Davide Ferrari</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Davide Ferrari</description><image><url>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/23432883</url><link>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/23432883</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 11:58:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ferraridavide.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Python to automate text overlays in Premiere Pro</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/automating-text-premiere-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 11:58:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/automating-text-premiere-pro/</guid><description>Recently, I embarked on a weekend project to create a video compilation of all the intros from the tech show TechLinked (which you can check out here). I figured it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to write any code, but as it turned out, I ended up having to resort to some Python to get the job done.
I had my Premiere Pro sequence all set up with all the intros chopped up and ready to go, but when I wanted to add text displaying the name and date of the current clip, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to do it in Premiere Pro.</description></item><item><title>Accessing Synology DSM internal databases and exporting Synology Photo albums</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/accessing-synology-dsm-database/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 22:55:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/accessing-synology-dsm-database/</guid><description>One of the reasons that lead me to finally get a Synology NAS was that i needed a simple and reliable way to solve the chaotic photo situation i had going on, all of my and my family’s photos were spread over multiple hard drives and other mediums, scattered in unorganized random folders, to put it simply, they were all over the place.
I was looking for a solution that is reliable, easily maintainable, and that would allow me to neatly organize all of my photos in a single place, something that has fine-grained control over photo access permissions with a user system, and with an intuitive enough user interface that my tech-illiterate family members could have easy access to our photos.</description></item><item><title>Skills</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/skills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferraridavide.github.io/skills/</guid><description>C#
I am highly proficient in C# and possess a deep understanding of it&amp;rsquo;s most advanced concepts, I am comfortable navigating complex projects and solutions. My knowledge of C# has allowed me to create a wide range of applications, from desktop software to web applications and services. I am confident in my ability to write robust, high-quality code in C#.
WPF
I have experience using WPF to create professional user interfaces for business-oriented desktop applications.</description></item></channel></rss>