<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Davide Ferrari</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Davide Ferrari</description><image><url>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/23432883</url><link>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/23432883</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 15:47:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Time at Maxidata</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/maxidata/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 15:47:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/maxidata/</guid><description>In the summer of 2020 I was wrapping up my first year of university. Like most of my classmates, I was still adjusting to this new environment and trying to find my way through classes and exams. It was a weird time—everything felt new, and on top of that, the world was in the middle of a global pandemic.
I first heard about Maxidata through word of mouth—a friend mentioned the company was looking for a software developer.</description></item><item><title>Aule UniPV: A simple way to find an empty classroom</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/aule-unipv-webapp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 08:36:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/aule-unipv-webapp/</guid><description>Since starting university, my class schedule has been all over the place, often leaving me with random gaps to fill. I’d end up wandering through the hallways of Nave, moving from building to building, trying to find an empty classroom where my friends and I could settle in.
So when the Web Technologies course asked us to create a project for the final exam, I already knew what I wanted to build.</description></item><item><title>Using Python to automate text overlays in Premiere Pro</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/automating-text-premiere-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 11:58:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/automating-text-premiere-pro/</guid><description>Recently, I embarked on a weekend project to create a video compilation of all the intros from the tech show TechLinked (which you can check out here). I figured it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to write any code, but as it turned out, I ended up having to resort to some Python to get the job done.
I had my Premiere Pro sequence all set up with all the intros chopped up and ready to go, but when I wanted to add text displaying the name and date of the current clip, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to do it in Premiere Pro.</description></item><item><title>Accessing Synology DSM internal databases and exporting Synology Photo albums</title><link>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/accessing-synology-dsm-database/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 22:55:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferraridavide.github.io/posts/accessing-synology-dsm-database/</guid><description>One of the reasons that lead me to finally get a Synology NAS was that i needed a simple and reliable way to solve the chaotic photo situation i had going on, all of my and my family’s photos were spread over multiple hard drives and other mediums, scattered in unorganized random folders, to put it simply, they were all over the place.
I was looking for a solution that is reliable, easily maintainable, and that would allow me to neatly organize all of my photos in a single place, something that has fine-grained control over photo access permissions with a user system, and with an intuitive enough user interface that my tech-illiterate family members could have easy access to our photos.</description></item></channel></rss>